







https://www.linkedin.com/in/pedropcruz/



# Introduction

Since the beginning of my journey as a frontend developer with design skills, I've built several products for all companies I've worked for, collaborated with talented people to create digital products for both business and consumer use. I'm quietly confident, avid learner, and positive thinkerer. I love to see tech conferences on youtube, learning new things about coding, love to travel with my wife to anywhere in the world. Have a nice dog and love to get out of home with my friends. I've been organizing freeCodeCamp meetups in Lisbon for the past years and I love to mentor new people to start their careers as software developers.

# **Education**

#### **Udemy Courses**

- Vuejs 2 The complete guide with Vuex and VueRouter
- GraphQL with React
- Advanced React and Redux
- Modern React with Redux
- The complete Nodejs Developer Course
- Node with React

#### **KCSIT**

- Android Basic Course
- iOS Basic Course
- SCRUM
- Javascript
- Presentation Techniques and Meetings Management
- Webapps Security

#### **Alphappl**

- C / C# / HTML5 / CSS3 / JS / Bootstrap / PHP / ASP.NET
- Windows Phone 8 Apps

#### Restart

- Quark Express
- Adobe Illustrator / Photoshop / Effects

# **Skills**

• HTML5 // CSS3 // JS // Sass // Less // React // Vue // Nuxt // styled-components // Bulma // Bootstrap // Redux // Vuex // Gatsby // Jest // Storybook // Vuepress

### **Tools**

• Sketch // Adobe Illustrator // Adobe XD // VSCode

# **Work Experience**

#### Piksel - Frontend Developer (Contractor)

07/2019 - 04/2020

- Bug fixing
- Helped maintain documentation for the project
- Worked with React, styled-components, Jest, Storybook

# Airbeem - Frontend Developer (Contractor)

05/2019 - 06/2019

- Working on features for a Video Streaming app
- Worked with Nuxt, Bulma, Sass, Jest, Storybook

#### RentLovers - Frontend Developer

05/2019 - 06/2019

- Responsible for UI/UX Layers
- Responsible for Frontend development, used the best coding practices
- Builted a platform to connect landlords with renters

## diconium - Software Engineer

11/2018 - 02/2019

- Leading an old project on retail market (eCommerce project), worked with javaspring, javascript, css, jQuery
- Worked as frontend developer for a mechanical parts eCommerce, worked with React, Sass, Apollo GraphQL, Node

#### **Grupo Impresa - Frontend Developer**

05/2016 - 11/2018

- Worked on new features / bug fixes on every branding website of a specific niche.
- Developed with javascript (es5), Twig Templating, Symphony Framework (PHP)

#### **KCSIT - Junior Consultant**

05/2016 - 11/2018

- Developed a new Backoffice for social marketing about a specific company.
- Built on javascript (vanilla), handlebars, HTML5/CSS3/Bootstrap

#### Viatecla - Junior Software Developer

10/2014 - 01/2015

- Responsible for UI/UX Design for a specific part of a complex project on tourism bussiness area
- Developed with Razor (HTML5/CSS3/Javascript(vanilla)), jQuery, Bootstrap. Everything under a MVC Pattern

#### **CDSI - Junior Software Developer**

10/2014 - 01/2015

- Developed a new backoffice for insurance companies
- Builded with ASP.NET, VB.NET, HTML5/CSS3/Javascript(vanilla), jQuery